<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bjørn Fjukstad</title>
    <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bjørn Fjukstad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fjukstad.github.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Data Science in DIPS</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/enabling-data-science-in-dips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/enabling-data-science-in-dips/</guid>
      <description>At DIPS we are currently productionizing our new electronic health record (EHR) system, DIPS Arena. With DIPS Arena we have made the move to store structured clinical data with openEHR. openEHR is an open technology for e-health systems that help different vendors to build interoperable systems for healthcare. In other words, it helps define the different clinical concepts, e.g. blood pressures, body temperatures etc, how we can represent them, and how we can retrieve them from systems that implement an openEHR API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soltimer Påsken 2020</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/sun-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/sun-hours/</guid>
      <description>Meteorologene på twitter skrev en tweet om hvor mange soltimer det hadde vært i påska.
Av bildet kan det se ut som om solene er skalert opp og ned basert på antall soltimer. Selv om Oslo har nesten 7 ganger så mange soltimer som Tromsø, virker det ikke som om at størrelsen på solene reflekterer dette. Her er et eksempel på hvordan man kunne lagd en lignende visualisering i R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to get started with technical writing for a while now. Hopefully, re-writing my fjukstad.github.io website to use hugo, and creating a /blog menu item on my website will get me started.
At the moment I am working on data analysis and visualization of covid-19 data for the company I work at, DIPS, and I believe that the first real post will be about just that. For those of you who do not know, DIPS is both the name of the company, and the name of the electronic patient health record systems used by the majority of Norwegian hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a (hopefully) updated list of my publications, talks etc.
Papers  Reproducible Data Analysis Pipelines for Precision Medicine. Bjørn Fjukstad, Vanessa Dumeaux, Michael Hallett, Lars Ailo Bongo. To appear in the proceedings of 2019 27th Euromicro International Conference On Parallel, Distributed and Network-based Processing (PDP). 2019. Teaching Electronics and Programming in Norwegian Schools Using the air:bit Sensor Kit. Bjørn Fjukstad, Nina Angelvik, Morten Grønnesby, Maria Wulff Hauglann, Hedinn Gunhildrud, Fredrik Høisæther Rasch, Julianne Iversen, Margaret Dalseng, Lars Ailo Bongo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m also doing my best to teach others! I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching at university and organizing the local Code Club in Tromsø for the last couple of years. On this page I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to list all of it below with some links to source code or other materials. Although I believe that everything I do at the University should be open, I was unfortunately not allowed to open-source everything I built for the uni courses!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>