<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Bjørn Fjukstad</title>
    <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Bjørn Fjukstad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing COVID-19 data at DIPS</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/openehr-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/openehr-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I published a post on how we enable data science at DIPS, which told the story on how we can get data from our openEHR server in the R programming language. To make things even more interesting, this post will show how we can get screening symptoms from COVID-19 patients registered in our openEHR Server in DIPS Arena. With this data we can create reports with R Markdown, beautiful Shiny dashboards, and open up for researchers to explore and analyze the data in their own environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>p5.js</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/p5js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/p5js/</guid>
      <description>In Bodø I help organize local the coding club. Because of the covid-19 situation we are hosting the club on Discord, rather than in person at the public library in Bodø. This afternoon the participants were working fairly idependent, so I had some time to sit down some more with p5.js.
p5.js is a great Javascript library for creating visual content in the web browser, e.g. animations, games, art etc. In short a p5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Data Science in DIPS</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/enabling-data-science-in-dips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/enabling-data-science-in-dips/</guid>
      <description>At DIPS we are currently productionizing our new electronic health record (EHR) system, DIPS Arena. With DIPS Arena we have made the move to store structured clinical data with openEHR. openEHR is an open technology for e-health systems that help different vendors to build interoperable systems for healthcare. In other words, it helps define the different clinical concepts, e.g. blood pressures, body temperatures etc, how we can represent them, and how we can retrieve them from systems that implement an openEHR API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soltimer Påsken 2020</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/sun-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/sun-hours/</guid>
      <description>Meteorologene på twitter skrev en tweet om hvor mange soltimer det hadde vært i påska.
Av bildet kan det se ut som om solene er skalert opp og ned basert på antall soltimer. Selv om Oslo har nesten 7 ganger så mange soltimer som Tromsø, virker det ikke som om at størrelsen på solene reflekterer dette. Her er et eksempel på hvordan man kunne lagd en lignende visualisering i R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to get started with technical writing for a while now. Hopefully, re-writing my fjukstad.github.io website to use hugo, and creating a /blog menu item on my website will get me started.
At the moment I am working on data analysis and visualization of covid-19 data for the company I work at, DIPS, and I believe that the first real post will be about just that. For those of you who do not know, DIPS is both the name of the company, and the name of the electronic patient health record systems used by the majority of Norwegian hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/p5js-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bjornfjukstad@gmail.com (Bjørn Fjukstad)</author>
      <guid>http://fjukstad.github.com/blog/p5js-trees/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>